A Guide to the Norfolk County (Va.), Lists of Black and White Families, 1782-1783.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lists of Black and White Families, 1782-1783.
The Library of Virginia
1161800-1161802
2 sheets and 12 p.
Chesapeake (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This item came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from City of Chesapeake Circuit Court.
Historical Information
Norfolk County was formed from Lower Norfolk County in 1691. Now extinct, Norfolk County was incorporated into the city of Chesapeake in 1963.
Scope and Content
Norfolk County (Va.) Lists of Black and White Families, 1782-1783. Consists of manuscript list of heads of households and the number of white and black residents of the household. Some lists include both free and enslaved persons while others include only free persons of color. These records are arranged with lists of tithables and taxable property for Norfolk County, but do not seem to have been collected for fiscal or taxation purposes, but simply as a head count. Accordingly, this separate inventory has been created for the records though they remain housed with the aforementioned tax and fiscal records.
Arrangement
The records are arranged chronologically by box.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Chesapeake (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Slaves -- Virginia -- Norfolk County.; Freedmen-- Virginia -- Norfolk County.
Geographical Names:
Chesapeake (Va.) -- History.; Norfolk County (Va.) -- History -- 18th century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Census records -- Virginia -- Norfolk County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Norfolk County.
Added Entry - Corporate Name:
Norfolk County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Contents List
- List of All Free Male Persons Above 21; Names of Slaves, Number of Cattle, Horses, Mares, and Colts from Great Bridge to Edmonds Bridge to New Mill Creek, 1782 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Number of White and Black In Each Family on the South Side of the Western Branch, by Charles Conner, 1782 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- List of White and Black Persons from the Ferry Point to the Great Bridge, by Samuel Veale, 1782 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- List of White and Black Persons Within the Borough of Norfolk and South Side of Tanners Creek, by James Taylor, 1782 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- List of Male Whites and Free Male Blacks Above the Age of 16 from Great Bridge to Edmunds Hill to New Mill Creek, by William Hall, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- List of All Whites and Blacks in the Precinct from the Great Bridge to Edmonds Bridge to New Mill Creek, by Daniel Sanford, 1782 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- List of Whites and Blacks in Each Family- North Side of Tanners Creek from Godfrey's to Sewells Point, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- List of the Families of Whites and Blacks on the South Side of the Western Branch as far as New Mill Creek, by William Booker, Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
- List of Families in St. Brides Parish, by William Hall, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- List of Free Males from Ferry Point to Great Bridge, by Samuel Veale, 1783 (Box 3, Folder 43)